Hello, this is the video about the first
exercise in ProPa (Programming Paradigms).
And this one we got right in front of us.
So here, the task is to draw a solid circle…
A yellow solid circle and a
green solid rectangle below it.
The result can also be shown
on a website. I opened it here.
So, this is how it should look.
And our task is to implement the scene
as a picture, which is given here.
So, write the implementation for “scene”.
So, for this task, use CodeWorld.
And there is a guide, which
you can see down below here.
I will open this one in a new tab.
This is the API of CodeWorld.
And we can use this one to find
all the functions that we require
in order to draw the rectangle and the circle.
First of all, let’s draw the rectangle.
Let’s search for “rectangle”
within the API. *presses Ctrl + f*
And there we have a function,
which is “rectangle”.
and a function “solidRectangle”.
And we want to try “solidRectangle”.
This is the one that we shall use.
And here it says a solid rectangle is
defined with its width and its height.
So, we have just two parameters. (as given here)
So, we can just draw a solid rectangle.
And let’s just say: 10 and 2 (in size).
And then we can use the
features of the CodeWorld API
that will draw our rectangle.
So now, we see that the rectangle is black.
We want to have a green rectangle.
It is also not wide enough;
so, this one covers the whole page, and this one,
maybe half of it.
So, how can we fix this?
The first parameter is the width,
as we can see that the object
is wide and not very tall.
We can do this by the numbers.
When we increase the size,
we should get a rectangle
which covers the whole page.
Let’s, first of all, do this.
Now we see… oh yeah, it covers the whole page.
And then we want to have this
rectangle in a different color.
So, let’s just do a search for “color”.
And there we have a function “colored” which
takes a Color and a Picture.
So, we can change the color of a Picture
by just applying this function.
And then we have colors
and there we have green defined.
So, we can simply use that one.
So: colored … (use green)
and then we apply the “solidRectangle”.
Also, here is an error message.
Something is wrong.
Of course, the second parameter
has to be in brackets.
So, we simply write it like this.
And if we apply this one, then
we get our green rectangle.
Now, that’s just a part of the story.
As we want to increase a Picture size…
Let's just say we want to
define our code a bit better.
So, let me extract this part here.
Let’s say we call this one “greenRectangle”
because we can name values in Haskell.
So, “greenRectangle” is defined
exactly as this one here.
So, now, running this one… again,
we get a green rectangle.
But there is something missing for
the green rectangle definition here,
which is a good way of implementing code,
because we have not said what
kind of value greenRectangle is.
But we actually know it is a Picture.
So, we can say greenRectangle is a Picture.
Apply this one here.
...
And secondly, we want a yellow circle.
Well... we have no yellow circle yet.
We can just say “yellowCircle = blank”
just to fill something in.
So, now it shall draw the green rectangle.
Now we have to define the yellow circle.
We can, again, look into the API
and search for “circle” because this is
what we want to define here as well.
There is an example given.
There is also the definition for this function.
So, this draws a thin circle, but we want to
have a solid circle. So, we use “solidCircle”.
And we just give the radius
in order to draw a circle.
We might just say: solidCircle…
and let’s just say the radius is 2.
It’s on top of our green rectangle.
But it is black and bigger.
Why is it bigger?
Because we have to give the radius.
And the rectangle is just 2 in height.
So, our circle shall be 2 in height.
It has to have the size 1.
And now we want to have our circle in yellow.
We need to color it.
Again, we can use “colored”
in order to change the color of the circle.
There is no error.
So, it seems we can use this function.
Yellow is a predefined color.
We can have it here.
Again, we haven’t said what
yellowCircle is a value of.
So, this is a Picture, again.
We defined yellowCircle as a Picture.
Now, the circle is not in the right place.
So, we have to move the circle somehow.
And therefore, we have a function
which is called “translated”, which translates
the Picture in these directions.
So, we have to give the values here.
We can say: translated… and then 2 values.
Let’s just say we have 4 and 0.
Let’s see how this turns out.
Oh… And we need to have this in brackets again.
So now, apply this one.
This is in the wrong direction.
We want to have this circle above the rectangle
and not on top of it.
So, we mixed up the values up here.
So, this is the horizontal value.
And this is the vertical one.
So, we should have something here.
Let’s just say 4 here and 0 here.
And we apply this one.
and we see our circle right above the rectangle.
Actually, it should be a
bit further away compared to
the picture on the right.
So, let’s maybe say 6.
And yeah, this looks quite good.
So now, we have drawn our green rectangle
and the yellow circle above it.
And we are done with this task.